#### Contact

aurelienbrachet123@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/aurélien-brachet-146556141 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

ReactJS

**TypeScript** 

Jest

### Languages

Français (Native or Bilingual)
Anglais (Professional Working)
Russe (Elementary)

### Certifications

REACTJS QUIZ NIVEAU INTERMÉDIAIRE REDUX QUIZZ INTERMEDIAIRE

# Aurélien Brachet

React Native/ReactJS developer France

### Summary

I am a freelance developer specializing in the ReactJS ecosystem with more than 5 years of experience using React for the web and mobile. Working primarily as a front-end developer with React Native. I have a master's specialized in computer sciences. I have been working on a wide variety of projects, mainly in France but also abroad.

## Experience

Prium Solutions
Development Lead ReactJS & React Native
July 2021 - October 2023 (2 years 4 months)
Remote

As a Lead Developer specializing in React JS and React Native, I led the complete overhaul of Prium Portage's internal website, which was burdened by a significant accumulation of technical debt. I conducted the selection process and provided recommendations regarding the technical stack to be adopted, including React Hook Form, Tailwind, Vite, Axios, XState, among others. I established a scalable architecture with unit tests while ensuring the implementation of user interfaces designed by the UI/UX design team.

Additionally, I worked on the development from scratch of the Prium One mobile application.

folk

Développeur React JS

May 2021 - June 2021 (2 months)

Remote

One month mission where I was helping to improve the test coverage of the application (Jest & react-testing-library)

Egis ReactJS developer March 2021 - May 2021 (3 months)

#### Remote

Development of a POC for the city of Amsterdam. This was a full remote month project where I have had the opportunity to discover new technologies of the ReactJS ecosystem:

- XState,
- ZeStand.

Log'in Line
React Native developer
July 2020 - September 2020 (3 months)
Remote

Short-term mission where I assisted in the development of the Fantasy Rugby World application.

Futur composé Lead React Native developer January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months) Caen, France

I was working on the Dokki application (https://apps.apple.com/tt/app/dokki-learn-play/id1524772965?ign-mpt=uo%3D2) as lead developer. I took charge of the project for 5 months and I was responsible for making the technical choices for the project. I implemented an architecture where the store was reused between the web app and mobile app part in TDD.

I also participated in the formation of juniors and work-study students in the company.

Redux, Redux Saga, Jest, Typescript.

### **FIDME**

React Native developer
March 2019 - August 2019 (6 months)
Bordeaux

Fidme is an application with over 1 million users, I have been working on the redesign of their application for 6 months in React Native.

I have also been working with Mobx and Jest during this project.

### dotmind

Développeur ReactJS freelance February 2019 - February 2019 (1 month)

Région de Bordeaux, France

Development of FFR TV for the new website of the French Rugby Federation in ReactJS.

- https://www.ffr.fr/ffr-tv

ACTUM Digital
Intern in React Native
September 2017 - December 2017 (4 months)
Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

It was my first internship Abroad, as a React Native developer..

During the job, I was mostly programming in React Native. I learnt how to handle multi languages application, building complex search logic through a list.

I learnt advance notion in React like HOC and Functional programming and how to work in team with employees from different country.

Alizarine
Intern in mobile development
January 2017 - April 2017 (4 months)
Bordeaux Area, France

My first internship as a React Native developer, in Bordeaux, France.

It consisted as a social media where people could share their best "sea spot" while traveling on a google map. I had no experiences in React Native at the time, so I had to learn everything during the development process.

I learnt how to structure my code the best way possible and learnt a lot of basic uses of React Native, like navigation, camera and redux.

Recreation center
Animator in a Sartilly center
August 2016 - August 2016 (1 month)
Sartilly

I had to manage children between 6 and 9 years old.

DALTONER
Internship as a network Technician
May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)
Avranches

Internship as a technician where I was helping companies and particular to resolve their IT's issues.

# Education

Exia cesi

Engineer degree, IT specialized in development · (2016 - 2019)

University of the West of Scotland

Erasmus Semester, Mobile development · (2018 - 2018)

Institut Lemonnier

Two years technical degree in IT, Informatique · (2014 - 2016)

Institut saint lô

A level, Scientifique · (2011 - 2014)